Biddut Kumar

Address: Mohadevpur, Naogaon

Phone: +8801738114274

E-mail: biddut.starlink@gmail.com

Linkedin: https://www.linkedin.com/in/biddut-kumar/

Career Objective:

In line with my continued interest and performance in Telecommunication sector. I have decided to build up my career in the professional field. I would like to show my immense aspiration to become a quick learner and to prove myself as a sincere person through extensive hard working and integrity to this field.

Career Summary:

I began my career as a Survey Team leader in Telecom Third-party company. It helps me learn how to talk consumers professionally .After 5 months later I join Step One Group(UTSP) as a System Engineer For Specially Microwave Link Project. Learn, work hard & promoted and After 2.5 Years later went Back again to Starlink Engineering Itd at my Previous Company. Then one day my golden opportunity came to edotco Group as a Transmission Specialist in Mymenshingh Zone.

Employment History:

Total Year of Experience: 4.9 Year(s)

1. Commissioning Engineer

2nd February 2020 To Ongoing

Fast Network Technology

Company Location: Uttara, Dhaka

Department: Operation

2. O & M Support

12th June 2018 To 30th September 2019

Edotco Bangladesh Co. Ltd

Company Location: JK Tower (3rd Floor) Town Hall, Mymensingh

Department: Operation

3. System Engineer

18th April 2017 To 11th June 2017

Starlink Engineering Ltd

Company Location: Mohakhali, Dhaka

Department: Operation

4. System Engineer

14st December 2014 To 16th February 2017

Unitech Telecom Service & Provider (UTSP) Company Location: Gulshan 1,

Dhaka Department: Operation



Academic Qualification:

Exam Title	Major	Institute	Result	Pass. Year	Duration
BSC	Electrical & Electronics Engineering	European University of Bangladesh	CGPA: 3.00 out of 4	2016	3.4 years
Diploma in Engineering	Electronics Technology	NSRTC	CGPA: 3.39 out of 4	2014	4 years

Training Information:

Training Title	Institute	Location	Year	Duration
Telecom Industrial Attachment	Unitech Telecom Service & Provider (UTSP)	Dhaka	2016	3 months
Industrial Attachment	Bangla Track Limited (Bangla CAT)	Dhaka	2012	3 months
Professional Spoken English	FM Method	Dhaka	2018	3 Months

Skills:

- Install and Commissioning Microwave Link, BTS, Rectifier.
- Maintain and secure power systems with all Alarming Configuration & TT Handling .
- Understand the principles of digital communication power system. 2G,3G,4G etc.
- Sound knowledge in Microsoft Office Word
- Sound knowledge in Microsoft Office Excel
- Knowledge In Adobe Photoshop CS

Language Proficiency:

Language	Reading	Writing	Speaking
Bangla	High	High	High
English	Medium	Medium	Medium

Personal Details:

Father's Name : Rabiranzon Mondal Mother's Name : Suchritarani Mondal Date of Birth : November 10, 1992

Gender : Male
Marital Status : Unmarried
Nationality : Bangladeshi
Religion : Hindu

Permanent Address : Mohadevpur, Naogaon

Reference (s):

Reference: 01 Reference: 02

Name : Abhilas Chandra Paul Name : Ratan Kumar Das

Organization : Edotco Bangladesh Co. Ltd Organization : Edotco Bangladesh Co. Ltd
Designation : Manager : Manager (Regional Operations)

Address : Dhaka Central Address : Dhaka Metro
Phone : +8801819550510 Phone : +8801833180839
Relation : Professional Relation : Professional